Many of us ponder what lies in outer space.
我们很多人都会思索外太空究竟存在着什么。
When we look up at the night sky, we see stars, the twinkle of a moving satellite and occasionally a distant planet.
当我们仰望夜空时，能看到繁星、移动卫星闪烁的光点，偶尔还能瞥见遥远的行星。
But one thing we don’t see is the millions of pieces of junk filling up space.
但有一样东西我们是看不到的，那就是充斥在太空中的数百万块垃圾。
It’s this debris that’s causing problems for the existing technology that’s up there and which we rely on.
正是这些太空碎片，给我们目前在轨运行且赖以生存的技术设备带来了麻烦。
The amount of space junk is increasing.
太空垃圾的数量正在不断增加。
Over the last few decades, satellites and rockets have been launched into space, littering the cosmos as they go.
在过去几十年里，人类向太空发射了大量卫星和火箭，这些设备在升空过程中也给宇宙留下了遍地狼藉。
It’s estimated there are now millions of discarded pieces of metal and other materials in orbit – everything from old rocket segments to accidentally dropped astronaut tools, and even flecks of paint.
据估计，如今轨道上漂浮着数百万块废弃的金属及其他材料碎片，比如老旧的火箭箭体，到宇航员不慎掉落的工具，甚至还有微小的油漆颗粒。
The fear is that if we don’t start taking this litter out of the sky soon, it will become a significant threat to active satellites.
人们担心，如果不尽快清理这些太空垃圾，它们将会对在轨运行的卫星构成严重威胁。
Nobu Okada, Chief Executive of Astroscale – a company working on ways to clean up space junk – says hitting “even a small paint fleck… has enough power to blow up other satellites.”
致力于研发太空垃圾清理技术的星舰公司首席执行官冈田伸表示，哪怕是一小块油漆颗粒，一旦发生撞击，其产生的威力也足以摧毁其他卫星。
Several ideas are being looked at to capture the debris floating around in space.
目前人们正在研究多种方案，用于捕获漂浮在太空中的碎片。
In 2018, the RemoveDebris spacecraft carried out various experiments, including testing a net that could snare a satellite and firing a harpoon at a target in orbit to try to catch it.
2018年，“太空清理”号航天器开展了多项实验，其中包括测试一种可捕获卫星的网，以及向轨道目标发射鱼叉以尝试捕捉碎片。
This year the UK Space Agency is helping to fund new approaches to tracking satellites and debris in space.
今年，英国航天局出资支持了多项追踪在轨卫星与太空碎片的新方案研究。
Jacob Geer from UKSA told the BBC: “Space surveillance and tracking is one of the key things we can do to keep safe those satellites we rely on now, and to make sure certain orbits don’t become inaccessible for future generations because there’s too much debris in them.”
英国航天局的雅各布·吉尔在接受BBC采访时表示：“太空监测与追踪是我们目前能采取的关键措施之一，既能保护我们当下依赖的卫星安全运行，也能避免部分轨道因碎片过多而变得无法使用，从而给后代留下可用的太空轨道资源。”
It’s clear that a solution is needed so a celestial deep clean can take place.
显然，我们亟需找到解决方案，来开展一场太空大扫除。
But looking to the future, like any litter problem, we need to look at ways of creating less – and that shouldn’t be the stuff of science fiction.
而放眼未来，和处理任何垃圾问题的思路一样，我们需要想方设法减少太空垃圾的产生——这绝非什么科幻情节，而是切实可行的举措。